Jordan Yuan

Email: yuanjor93@gmail.com Website: www.jordan-yuan.com

> Cell: 217-294-1984 Github: yuanjor93

Professional Summary

Software Developer with over four years of experience specializing in creating both single page applications and multi-page applications in an enterprise setting. Continuous learner passionate about technology, Hackathons, and developer conferences, and seeks to further integrate new technologies and frameworks in the workplace through an Agile methodology.

EXPERIENCE

• FedEx (Contract - TekSystems)

Milwaukee, WI

Software Developer February 2020 - Present

- Created Jenkins pipelines for Shipment Gateway and Package Dispatch Tracking applications in alignment with CI/CD best practices.
- Constructed information points in AppDynamics to track key telemetry metrics such as call volume, error count, and response time.
- Compiled on-boarding documentation and facilitated training of new team members on tools and processes to accelerate integration into the team.

• RW Baird (Contract - Codeworks)

Milwaukee, WI

Business Process Engineer

February 2019 - December 2020

- Worked with project teams to create both backend services, using Java 8, and frontend form logic, using Javascript, for client facing web applications and process workflow related to PWM, check transactions, wire, and ACH request processes in order to reduce risk by automating the approval process of financial transactions.
- Used the LiquidOffice design application to build and support business forms and processes. Utilized
 JUnits tests and Selenium automation tool, to create process automated tests and increase code quality
 for the Client Account Support team.
- Created additional deployment pipelines, using Go Pipeline, to deploy jar files and Java packages to testing environments and Production.
- Resolved critical incidents within the Production environment, identified alerts, and monitored
 Production servers with the non-technical client support team. Based on client feedback, implemented
 UI and backend feature improvement to ensure the application was FINRA compliant and to improve
 the client experience.

• American Family Insurance

Madison, WI

Application Developer

June 2015 - August 2018

- Created an enterprise premium calculation application using Typescript, through the Angular 5 framework, to upgrade internal existing systems into a singular web-app.
- Trained new team members on insurance rating applications and complex rating algorithms, in Typescript, based on business requirements and industry standards.
- Performed production support and on-call as part of the SDLC. Resolved critical and high priority bugs to ensure minimal financial impact to the business.
- Constructed services and components, through the Angular HttpClient and RxJs libraries, to create observables/GET requests of our internal business applications. Based on the business requirements, mapped the incoming JSON response into its corresponding UI values through two-way binding.

• Communicated effectively with business analysts to ensure product requirements were met. Constructed the core application based on the requirements in reusable patterns to increase developer productivity and improve code quality.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION

• Grinnell College

Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science

Grinnell, IA

September 2011 - June 2015

- Guidewire 7 Configuration Certification August. 2015
- Guidewire 7 Integration Certification August. 2015
- Guidewire 8 Rating Self-Certification September. 2015

PROJECTS

- Node JS Blogger (current): Using Node.js, building a blogging app used to experiment with different JS libraries and learn other JS frameworks.
- Envision (current): S.P.A. incorporating Restful Services to display stock and Crytocurrency data build upon the Angular 8.2 framework
- **PocketRocket:** Created a web-based game using Unity Engine and C#. Players are able to navigate through a series of puzzles based on rocket physics.
- American Family VR Hackathon (3rd Place): Constructed a VR real time map using Android Java Google VR kit. Enabled the business to improve advertisement experience based on customers preference and geographic data.
- MuMuRun: Using Android Java, created a mini mobile game with the AndEngine and custom sprites.

Programming Skills

- Programming Languages: Java, GoSu, JavaScript, Typescript, C, XML, HTML, LateX
- **Technologies**: Windows, TFS, Slack, MacOS, Unix, Visual Studio Code, Git, Bitbucket, Intellj, Microsoft Office Suite, RESTful services, Selenium